HASHMATULLAH AFROZ

Crawley, Gatwick London, Southgate Avenue, Crawley, West Sussex RH106LW | +447424132003 | zaherhashmatullah1@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an experienced software developer. I bring more than three years experience writing PHP full-stack applications, javascript, Django and more than two years experience in the technology industry. Duo to my qualification, extensive background, training, I am interested to apply for the vacant position and join your respected team. That will be really kind of you if you do a closer look at the particulars of my education and skills which you find on my CV. I am very confident of Management, Supervision, Monitoring, evaluation, Coordinating, reporting, Analysing, interpreting, team work, have good speaking voice, neat and respectable appearance, Ability and willingness of working outside normal office hours

EXPERIENCE

01/2019 to 02/2022

Freelance Web Developer

Fron-End & Backend Devleopment using WAMP & MERN stack technologies — Kabul

- Contributed to back-end experience and collaborated on APIs.
- Built reusable code that could be utilised in other projects, saving company time.
- Produced and updated website to facilitate daily visitors.
- Improved web design and usability through UX testing.

01/2021 to 01/2022

Freelancer

Diamond Gym — Kabul

- I developed a CMS for the gym, it was a localhost database and i was maintain the database to them
- Planned and organised strategic campaigns for local businesses.

01/2018 to 01/2020

Customer care

AWCC(Afghan wireless communication)

- Customer care
- Greeting the customers offer them credit cards and also i was saling the cards in one side
- Carried out regular training with staff to help advance skills within customer care, effective complaint handling and service improvement tactics.
- Prepared products for placing on shelves, including wrapping, packaging and portioning, completing according to company guidelines.
- Communicated with clients to obtain a better understanding of needs and make recommendations on appropriate products.

01/2016 to 01/2017

Exam Invigilator

British Council — Kabul

- Invigilator
- Control and organize candidates during exam day
- Ensured candidates did not talk once inside the examination.
- Communicated with other invigilators on possible student malpractice and reported to examination body.
- Supervised students throughout the examination to deter cheating.
- Distributed examination papers and other materials.
- Supervised the exam for the duration of time.
- Monitored and quickly implemented required curriculum changes.

01/2016 to 01/2016 Teacher

i cacilei

- Azerakhsh Academic Centre Kabul
 - Planned and implemented lessons utilising variety of teaching strategies to meet diverse student needs.
 - Prepared unit and lesson plans for courses of study, following curriculum guidelines and common core standards.
 - Designed compelling lesson plans focused on literature and writing learning goals for classes.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Basics of C/C++ programming language
 C# Programming language game
- development (Unity)

 Basics of Java
- Programming Language
 JavaScript Full-Stack Developer (JQuery.js,
- React.js, Express.js)Basics of Python Programming Language
- FRONT-END Web development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JQuery,

React.JS

BACK-END(Server)
 Development :
 Laravel(PHP), PHP PDO,
 Express.JS (Node.js),
 MVC pattern,

- Basics of Django (python) MVT pattern
- DATABASE Development: MySQL(RDBMS), MangoDB(non-relational),
- Mobile Development : React-Native(JavaScript)

SQLlite3(RDBMS)

- IOS and Android

 Networking and
- reconnaissance (PT)
 Familiar with Linux OS
 Freelancer management
- Problem-solving

EDUCATION

2022 Certificate of Higher Education: Computer Science,

Software Engineering **Bakhtar Unversity** — Kabul

2017 Diploma of Higher Education

Habibya High School — Kabul

GPA: 89.89

2016 Certificate of Higher Education: English literature

Azerakhsh Academic — Kabul

HASHMATULLAH AFROZ

REFERENCES

REFERENCE Bezhan Rasuly - "AWCC" Team Leader +93700801773

LANGUAGES

- Dari
- Pashto
- English
- Urdu
- Arabic

PROJECTS

- Gym Management: Manipulating data, creating reports, Authorization, authentication And so on
- Restaurant: Creating reports, Analysing Data, manipulating data and so on
- School Admin panel for front-end using Laravel and JQuery.js